Alena Nikulina

New York, NY | 302-344-1536 | alenanikulina0@gmail.com

Github | LinkedIn | Medium

Frontend Web Developer

Front-end web developer with experience as a full stack engineer. Passion for writing beautiful code that makes an impact. Years of experience in customer facing roles. Collaborative with well honed leadership and organizational skills. Team player with the ability to work independently to drive results. Committed to using the power of technology to shape the world. Enjoys learning about and evaluating new technologies and frameworks. Loves to travel and explore new cultures, cuisines and experiences.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML | CSS | Javascript | ReactJS | Redux | RESTful API architecture | Ruby | Ruby on Rails | Git

PROJECTS

Taste of Russia - Github-Frontend | Github-Backend | Demo

Browse, search and save Russian recipes

- Developed a Rails API backend for data fetching and persistence
- Implemented React for user interface and Redux for state management
- Used Redux middleware to respond to and modify state changes
- Used react-router in conjunction with RESTful routing convention

AdventureGaze - Github-Frontend | Github-Backend | Demo

Browse destinations and save them to your profile with desired travel dates

- Developed a Rails API backend for destinations and their descriptions
- Implemented user interface employing JavaScript and CSS
- Used JavaScript to render JSON on show pages
- Handled all interactions between the client and the server asynchronously (AJAX)

BeautyVerse - Github | Demo

Rails application for researching makeup brands and their products

- Utilized MVC architecture to ensure that the application has a specific organizational structure
- Created models, migrations, controllers and routes for viewing brands, products and reviews
- Implemented Activerecord gem for mapping Ruby objects into a relational database
- Adhered to RESTful design principles to have a clear and standardized naming structure for routes and actions

EXPERIENCE

BLT Prime Restaurant, New York, NY - Captain

05/2015 - 11/2018

- Maintained detailed knowledge of menu items and ingredients used to drive sales
- Provided wine presentations and recommendations to a discerning clientele
- Collaborated with the kitchen staff to maximize customer satisfaction

Papillon Bistro and Bar, New York, NY - Bartender

10/2012 - 04/2015

- Developed good working relationships with co-workers and the management team
- Met and exceeded all guest requests and expectations with professional attitude

EDUCATION

Flatiron School

07/2019 - 03/2020

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

Omsk State University, Omsk, Russia

2005-2010

Coursework completed towards a Bachelor of Arts degree in English